wit.ie 2019-04-18

# Privacy Statement | Waterford Institute of Technology

### WIT web and online Privacy Statement

The Institute’s web and online privacy statement is an organic document which changes frequently as our technologies change and the information provided here is constantly being reviewed in line with the Data Protection Acts, 1988 and 2003 and with EU General Data Protection Regulation 2018.

This webpage was last updated on Thursday, 24 May 2018

* * *

### Privacy statement

The Institute fully respects your right to privacy and actively seeks to preserve the privacy rights of those who share information with the Institute. The Institute will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your permission, except as may be required or permitted by law. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be up front about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it. Any personal information which you volunteer to the Institute will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, in accordance with the Data Protection Acts, 1988 and 2003 and with EU General Data Protection Regulation 2018.

### Collection and use of personal information

Any information which you provide is not made available to any third parties unless clearly stated on the webpage, and is used by the Institute only in accordance with the purpose for which you provided the information and will only be retained for as long as required for the purpose. This is normally stated on the webpage where the information is requested and should be self-explanatory.

### ExpressionEngine

We use a third-party cms (content management system), ExpressionEngine.com, to run our website. ExpressionEngine adds a number of cookies to the browser which are essential for wit.ie to work and these are considered as necessary cookies. For more information about how ExpressionEngine processes data, please see [**ExpressionEngine's privacy notice**](https://expressionengine.com/privacy\)).

### Website analytics

When someone visits our website, we use a third-party service, Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. See [**Google's privacy policy**](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html).

### Cookies

You can read more about how we use cookies on our **Cookies page**.

### Search engine

Our website search is powered by Google Search. Search queries and results are logged anonymously to help us improve our website and search functionality. No user-specific data is collected by either WIT or any third party. See [**Google's privacy policy**](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html).

### Security and performance

We use the Cloudflare service to maintain the security and performance of the WIT website. To deliver this service it processes individual site visitors and applies security settings on a per-visit basis. This data is not available to WIT and is anonymously used to ensure site security.  See [**Cloudflare’s privacy policy.**](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/)

### Online Forms

WIT uses a third-party supplier, Cognito Forms, to gather important information around events, scholarships, application forms etc. We collect only required information and will tell you why we are gathering that information in each form. This information is not shared with any third party, unless clearly stated. For more information, see [**Cognito Form’s privacy statement**](https://www.cognitoforms.com/privacy).

### Snacktools

We use a third-party service, Snacktools, to embed image galleries and interactive books on our website. We only publish images where consent has been granted. For more information, please see [**Snacktool’s privacy policy**](https://www.snacktools.com/en/legal-information/privacy-policy/).

### Video embedding

We embed video on the website using a third party, YouTube, to enhance your experience of content on our site. We only publish videos where consent has been granted. You can find out about [**YouTube’s Cookie policy**](https://www.google.com/chrome/browser/privacy/).

### Social Media Aggregator

We use a third-party provider, Juicer.io, as a simple way to aggregate the institute’s social media posts. Juicer does not collect any data from people who merely view Juicer social feeds that are embedded on a website. For more specifics about the types of data collected by Juicer, please refer to their [**Privacy Policy**](https://www.juicer.io/privacy).

### Targeted emails

We use a third-party provider, Mailchimp, to deliver emails to targeted groups. We only use lists where we have already gathered consent and delete lists regularly. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our communications. For more information, please see [**Mailchimp’s privacy notic**](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)e.

### Social Media Sharing and Integration

We use Facebook, Twitter and Instagram functionality within this site so that you can share items of interest, or become a follower of our Social Media Profiles. You can find out more about Facebook’s Cookie use [**here**](http://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=115180708570932) and [**Twitter’s here**](https://twitter.com/privacy) and [**Instagram's privacy policy**](https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388).

### WordPress

We use a third-party service, WordPress.org, to publish some of our microsites. These sites are hosted at WordPress.com, which is run by Automattic Inc. We use a standard WordPress service to collect anonymous information about users' activity on the site, for example the number of users viewing pages on the site, to monitor and report on the effectiveness of the site and help us improve it. For more information about how WordPress processes data, please see [**Automattic's privacy notice**](https://automattic.com/privacy/).
